Contact

leannphelps@sbcglobal.net

www.linkedin.com/in/lesliephelps-msn-rn-nea-bc-13603378 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Education
Process improvement
Management

Certifications
NEA-BC

Leslie Phelps MSN,RN,NEA-BC

Director of Nursing at Parkland Hospital Dallas. Texas

Summary

Experienced Director Of Nursing with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Customer Service, Patient Advocacy, Nursing Education, Business Process Improvement, and Patient Safety. Strong healthcare services professional with a MSN focused in Nursing Administration from The University of Texas at Arlington.

Experience

Parkland Hospital
Director of Nursing
June 2016 - Present (4 years 2 months)
Dallas, Texas

American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG)
Maternal Care Site Surveyor
March 2018 - Present (2 years 5 months)
Texas

Collin College
Adjunct Professor
August 2012 - August 2016 (4 years 1 month)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Professor Clinical Instruction Labor & Delivery, Post Partum, NICU, Pediatrics, OR, Medical Surgical, Emergency Services

Texas Health Resources
Director Of Nursing
February 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 4 months)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Labor & Delivery, Mother Baby, NICU, Pediatrics, Obstetrical Emergency Services

Methodist Health System
Director Of Nursing
October 2011 - February 2015 (3 years 5 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Labor & Delivery, Post Partum, Newborn Nursery, NICU, Obstetrical Emergency Services

Baylor Scott & White Health
Manager
September 2009 - October 2011 (2 years 2 months)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Antepartum - High Risk Obstetrics

Medical City Healthcare (Formerly HCA North Texas)
Manager
April 1989 - September 2009 (20 years 6 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Labor and Delivery, Post Partum

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington MSN, Nursing Administration · (2010 - 2012)

The University of Texas at Arlington BSN, Nursing · (2008 - 2010)

Collin College

ADN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1991 - 1993)